Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Photographs, circa 1897?-2001 (bulk 1900-1967); 4.9 Linear feet
  - Photos, 1960, circa 1960 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    Includes negatives of HRL in Taiwan by Lawrence K. Chang; HRL with John F. Kennedy in the TIME-LIFE building; group shot around a table with John F. Kennedy; a color photo of HRL at a Yale Alumni Day; contact sheets of the visit of Colombian President Alberto Lleras Camargo to the TIME-LIFE building; HRL and Roy E. Larsen with a group of Time Inc. news directors; various HRL portraits by Walter Bennett; HRL at the dedication of the Americas Plaza at the new TIME-LIFE building; HRL with Governor Rockefeller and David Sarnoff talking as part of the New York State Defence Council; HRL with Roy Alexander; group shot with HRL at the Lotos Club state dinner for Admiral Arleigh Burke; and HRL testifying at the Jackson Sub-Committee Hearings.
  - Photos, 1961, circa 1961 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    Includes a large number of different passport photos of HRL; various photos of HRL sitting with Dwight D. Eisenhower in his office in Pennsylvania; man holding up a cue card for the LIFE 25th anniversary special; HRL at the China Institute pointing to a Chinese book; HRL being presented with the Avenue of the Americas Key Man of the Year award by John Muller; HRL at the meeting of the East Texas Pulp and Paper Company; contact sheet with portraits of HRL by Alfred Eisenstaedt; HRL with Bob Hope; and HRL with Henry Cabot Lodge.
  - Majorca Portraits, 1962 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    Contains multiple portraits of HRL made by Alfred Eisenstaedt; one is a color print. Also includes a page proof of an ad "'Citizen Luce' Would Have Made a Lousy Movie."
  - Majorca Portraits for Public Relations Giveout, 1962 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    Contains multiple portraits of HRL by Alfred Eisenstaedt.
  - 1962 Miscellaneous, circa 1962 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    Includes a photo of HRL being presented with the Kappa Alpha Mu Founder's Award; HRL speaking at the TIME advertising convention; HRL presenting the Sherman Fairchild International Air Safety Writing Award; various photos of HRL at the College of Wooster; HRL at the annual New York alumni dinner of the Hotchkiss School; HRL with John M. Vorys; and HRL with Henry Luce III sitting in front of a large map.
  - TIME's 40th Anniversary Cover Party, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Lyndon Johnson, HRL with Francis Cardinal Spellman, Dean Rusk, Clarence Dillon and Clare Boothe Luce, and other photos of HRL mingling with the guests.
  - 1963 Miscellaneous, circa 1963 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    Includes multiple photos of HRL with General MacArthur; HRL receiving the Knight Commanders' Cross of the Order of Merit from the Federal Republic of Germany; HRL speaking from a podium; a group shot with HRL raising his glass; HRL talking with students at Brandeis University; HRL with Air University Board of Visitors; HRL with former King Umberto II of Italy, Cardinal Spellman, and Governor and Mrs. Rockefeller at Alfred E. Smith Memorial Dinner; contact sheets with Madame Nhu, her daughter and Clare Boothe Luce; HRL speaking at the World Law Conference in Athens; HRL with John Johnson; and HRL in cap and gown at Adelphi University.
  - HRL with Hedley Donovan, 1964 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    Includes a contact sheet with views of HRL's empty office. Most of the photos are by Alfred Eisenstaedt.
  - 1964 Miscellaneous, circa 1964 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    Includes negatives and contact sheets of HRL at a magazine publishers event; HRL on the podium at the Waldorf Astoria for the Harry Johnson Fisher Award; a contact sheet of HRL being presented with the 1964 Socratic award by the Order of Ahepa; HRL with Henry Luce III and others at the Taiwan airport; HRL with Henry Luce III and others at the opening of the Los Angeles Times New York office; HRL with Hedley Donovan and various photos of the Luce-Donovan dinner; HRL with James A. Rhodes; HRL in Cleveland with Louis B. Seltzer, James A. Rhodes and Allen James Lowe; HRL at the 1964 political convention; HRL with Charles Galvin and Robert G. Storey standing in front of the Umphrey Lee Memorial to the Rule of Law; HRL accepting the Great Leaders Award from Robert G. Storey; a bust of Socrates; HRL with Queen Frederika and daughter Irene (of Greece and Denmark); HRL at the San Francisco Republican National Convention?; HRL at a meeting of the Graphic Arts?; and HRL with Jesse Birnbaum.
  - Photos, 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 175, Folder 5)
    Includes a photo of HRL speaking before the Magazine Publishers Association; HRL at the 50 Million Fund for the Presbyterian Church meeting; HRL with Charles S. Rhyne and Richard Nixon at the World Conference on World Peace Through Law; HRL with Alfred Eisenstaedt; closeups of HRL at the Pacem in Terris Conference; group shot with HRL following the honorary degree award from Williams College; HRL with Chancellor Ludwig Erhard; HRL talking with students at Yale; HRL with Gov. Nelson Rockefeller and James Rorimer at the Exhibit of Chinese Art Treasures at the Metropolitan Museum of Art and other photos from a benefit tea event for the exhibit; HRL with Dr. Edler G. Hawkins at the annual Churchmen's Dinner in Honor of Presbyterian Men in Government and photos with other attendees; HRL at the 87th annual Yale Daily News banquet; HRL at Dr. Chandran's? inaugural lecture at the Union Theological Seminary; various HRL portraits; HRL on the phone at his vacation home in Phoenix, AZ; Clare Boothe Luce with Margaret Bourke-White in front of a large globe; group shots with HRL, Clare Boothe, Bourke-White and others; and HRL with Goodwin Knight, Richard Nixon, and Richard Casey at the IIDC Conference.
  - Photos, 1966, 1966-1969 (Box 175, Folder 6)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Major General C. E. Combs and Dr. Novice G. Fawcett being briefed on a visit to the Air Force Institute of Technology (AFIT) and other group shots with HRL's during the same visit; HRL at George Hunt's LIFE dinner showing something to a group of musicians; HRL with Madeleine Richards and Ed Warner at a TIME staff dinner; contact sheet with portraits of HRL; group shot with HRL at TIME's businessman's tour of Eastern Europe; HRL receiving an award at the Syracuse University School of Journalism; HRL with Thanat Khoman at the Foreign Policy Association luncheon; HRL at the Paul Hoffman dinner; HRL with General Milton G. Baker reviewing the corps of Valley Forge Military Academy; negatives of the TIME staff party (hunt ball) by Martha Holmes; HRL with Blagoje Lazic, Deputy Editor-in-Chief- of Yugoslav newspaper Borba; various photos of HRL with Josip Broz Tito; various photos of HRL at the 50 Million Fund for the Presbyterian Church dinner; HRL with Alfred Eisenstaedt; group shot with HRL in cap and gown after receiving an honorary doctorate at Yale; HRL at the dedication of the Severinghaus Library at the Heverford School; HRL at the Boeing's 50th anniversary party; and original signed letters from John Marin with an enclosed colored group shot with HRL.
  - 1967 Miscellaneous (Box 175, Folder 7)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Marshall Berges; HRL portraits taken in Santa Barbara; front cover of TIME with a portrait of HRL; and multiple photos of HRL with Kingman Brewster, Jr. and Reuben A. Holden at the Yale Alumni Day.
  - Luce, Henry III, circa 1930-1990 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    Includes Luce III with his wife Claire at Fisher Island (by Ted Bell); younger and older portraits of Luce III (by Nancy Kessler, David Gahr, Robbin Arnold, and others); on stage at the Thomas Jefferson Awards; standing next to Estes Kefauver and other individuals; posing in London (by T. Spencer); receiving an award from Dan O. Henry; wearing a military uniform with HRL at a Pan Am party; together with HRL holding a dead goose; together with HRL sitting in front of a large map; in naval uniform before going on convoy service; as a teenager next to another boy (Peter Paul Luce?); very young Luce III next to a small child (Peter Paul Luce?); raising a gun next to an instructor?; with other children at HRL's Mepkin estate; aboard a boat; and individual photos of Mrs. Henry Luce III.
  - Luce, Henry W., 1952 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    Contains a photograph of H. W. Luce's calling card in Chinese.
  - Luce, Sheldon, circa 1939-1945 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    Contains two photographs and a negative of Sheldon Luce sitting behind a desk holding a cigarette.
  - HRL's Memorial and Funeral Services (2 folders), 1967 (Box 176, Folder 1-2)
    Includes color transparency slides of HRL's burial at Mepkin, SC by Alfred Eisenstaedt; a shot of the Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church facade and the milling crowd; Clare Boothe Luce with Henry Luce III; Hedley Donovan; and mostly contact sheets with scenes of arriving mourners, shots from inside and outside of the church, scenes from inside the TIME-LIFE building, and at the ceremony in Mepkin.
  - HRL with Clare Boothe Luce (2 folders), circa 1934-1967 (Box 176, Folder 3-4)
    All of the photos have HRL and CBL by themselves or with other individuals. Includes HRL and CBL at the premier of "A Midsummer Night's Dream"; in Honolulu wearing leis; outside of a plane; in a cornfield at Mepkin; arriving at NY from Rome; at Alhambra, Spain; at various events; with Winston Churchill; at the visit of Premier Scelba; welcoming the Chilean President, Gabriel Gonzalez Videla; attending the opening of the play "Winged Victory"; on the beach; standing next to a voting booth; in Hong Kong; walking out of a plane to attend the Milan Fair; walking; standing or sitting as a couple; with Representative William J. Fulbright; CBL wearing a flight suit?; with Francis Cardinal Spellman; hunting; on a ship; picnicking in Spain; next to Wendell Willkie at a United China Relief rally; and at the Valley Forge Military Academy.
  - Misellaneous (2 folders), circa 1932-1967 (Box 176, Folder 5-6)
    Includes a photo of HRL in cap and gown receiving an honorary degree; group shot with HRL dressed as a miner in front of the "Mine Supt. Office" sign; various portraits of HRL; HRL with Clare Booth Luce; Jo Davidson and HRL's bust; HRL with Mr. Levy of the Hecht Co.; HRL with Roy Larsen; HRL with Charles S. Rhyne and Richard Nixon; HRL with a man holding a WDSU microphone; at a reception for the Poor Richard Club Award given to Clare Boothe Luce; group shot from a Texas? event with a large number of autographs on the back; HRL at an Italian Defense Ministry event?; HRL at the opening of "Candida"; HRL with Ludwig Erhard; HRL holding a Pan Am brochure?; HRL wearing a monocle; HRL shaking hands with Jackie Robinson at an Urban League dinner; negative of a pen and ink sketch of HRL; negatives of HRL with Pope Pius XII; an original sketch of HRL signed by Paul H?; negatives of a group shot with HRL and senior Time Inc. staff; and a slide of the HRL portrait by Charles Fox.
    In addition there are a large number of cutouts from contact sheets and other small photos with HRL reading, playing tennis, wearing a cowboy hat, eating, without a shirt and wearing a swimming cap, hunting, on a beach, climbing a rope, next to a microscope, and generally relaxing.
  - United States Forces in Austria (USFA) Photo Album, circa 1945-1946 (Box FF2)
    Album related to HRL's visit to Austria. Photographs include scenes of HRL arriving; shaking hands; shots of him talking with unidentified individuals in military and civilian clothing; groups of other individuals; street scenes, and dinner scenes. Also includes an autographed photo of General Mark W. Clark who appears in a number of other photos. A military patch of the USFA has become detached from the cover and is inside the album.
  - Oversize Photographs (Box -, Folder -)
  - Undated Photos, circa 1950-1972, 2001 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    Includes a photo of a 2001 Henry R. Luce Award statue for general excellence given to John Huey, managing editor of FORTUNE; HRL in a tuxedo standing between two men at an unidentified event; closeup portraits of HRL; HRL speaking at a podium; and HRL standing near Winston Churchill at a dinner in Churchill's honor?
  - Portraits of HRL by Yousuf Karsh (folder 1 of 2), 1944 (Box 180, Folder 2)
    Most of the photos are signed by Karsh.
  - Portraits of HRL by Yousuf Karsh (folder 2 of 2), 1944 (Box OS-Small)
  - Photos Prior to 1945 and Miscellaneous, circa 1920-1945 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    Includes a group shot with HRL, Briton Hadden and other members of the Yale Daily News board; HRL with a briefcase outside of a plane; HRL holding a pair of chopsticks sitting next to Edith Willkie?; HRL holding a cigarette; HRL sitting on the ground with enlarged covers of TIME, LIFE, and FORTUNE in the background; HRL with Warren? at a reception; various shots of HRL in cap and gown at Boston University with, among others, John Cowles, Arthur T. Roff, and Daniel L. Marsh; shots of HRL sitting on a couch inside his house in Mepkin; close-up of HRL sitting in an office?; and HRL sitting on stage behind an unidentified speaker.
  - Photos, 1946-1950 (Box 180, Folder 4)
    Includes a photo of HRL next to Winston Churchill at Churchill's honorary dinner?; HRL sitting in an office with Roy Larsen; solitary shots of HRL; HRL with Roy Larsen and another man looking at an issue of TIME; HRL with Theodore M. Greene at the LIFE "Pursuit of Happiness" Roundtable Conference; HRL with Owen D. Young and Bruce Barton congratulating the winner and runner-up in the first NY Press Association-Syracuse University scholarship contest; group shot with HRL in cap and gown; group shot with HRL at a corporate outing?; HRL with Mr. and Mrs. Robert McCormick; and HRL with Roy Alexander and Harry Truman presenting the latter with a portrait from a recent TIME cover.
  - Photos, 1951-1955 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Chiang Kai-shek in Taipei, Taiwan; various HRL portraits; HRL with Winston Churchill in Italy; HRL wearing a monocle at a Paris lunch with local Time Inc. bureau staff; HRL addressing attendees of the IIDC confernce from the podium; HRL with Italian Premier Scelba; HRL with Mr. Karnow? and Frank White in Paris; HRL on podium making a missionary speech at the San Francisco Opera House; an original signed letter from Thomas D. McAvoy with an attached photo of the Paris lunch; and group shot with HRL presenting a portrait to Harry Truman.
  - Photos (folder 1 of 2), 1956-1960 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    Photographs in matted paper frames or glued to cardboard. Includes a group shot with HRL at the William R. Knox annual pre-Christmas luncheon; group shots at a horse race for the "SPORTS ILLUSTRATED Purse"; and multiple HRL portraits by Halsman.
  - Photos (folder 2 of 2), 1956-1960 (Box 180, Folder 7)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Clare Boothe Luce talking to John and Jackie Kennedy; HRL speaking at the dedication of American Plaza in front of the new TIME-LIFE building; portrait of HRL; HRL being presented with a wallaby by Alan G. Langton; HRL with Konrad Adenauer and others; HRL with Len Hall and the Republican National Committee?; HRL with a trans-Atlantic pilot aboard a plane; HRL boarding a plane at Ciampino airport in Italy; HRL speaking at the International Industrial Development Conference (IIDC); HRL speaking at the LIFE war art presentation to the Pentagon; and group shots with HRL and Time Inc. Board of Directors.
  - Portraits of HRL by Ormond Gigli, circa 1958-1967 (Box 180, Folder 8)
    Contains six color transparencies.
  - Photos (folder 1 of 2), 1961-1967, 1972 (Box 181, Folder 1)
    Includes multiple photos of HRL in the White House with Lyndon B. Johnson by Yoichi Okamoto (one original autographed "To Henry Luce from his friend - Lyndon B. Johnson"); HRL sitting in an office with Dwight D. Eisenhower; HRL with Charles S. Rhyne and Richard Nixon; group shot with HRL next to the "TIME & LIFE Building" sign; HRL at the Republican National Convention?; HRL's Majorca portraits taken by Alfred Eisenstaedt; HRL and Clare Boothe Luce at a party in Chicago; HRL at Pacem in Terris World Peace Conference; HRL with Hedley Donovan; HRL speaking at the Luce-Donovan dinner; HRL with General MacArthur; HRL with Ludwig Erhard; and various shots of HRL at Boeing's 50th anniversary party.
  - Photos (folder 2 of 2), 1961-1967 (Box 181, Folder 2)
    Includes a photo of HRL with Charles S. Rhyne and Richard Nixon, HRL with Lyndon B. Johnson; multiple photos from HRL funeral service by Alfred Eisenstaedt; HRL with Ludwig Erhard; HRL at the Pacem in Terris World Peace Conference; portraits of HRL taken in Majorca by Eisenstaedt; close-ups of HRL at the Economic Roundtable; HRL at the World Law Conference in Athens; HRL receiving the Socratic award from the Order of Ahepa; HRL with Hedley Donovan; HRL at the Fund for the Republic event; and group shot with HRL and Time Inc. executives? sitting at a roundtable.
  - HRL's Portrait Painting by Charles Fox, circa 1965-2000 (Box 181, Folder 3)
    Contains color photos and transparencies of the painting.
  - Majorca and Other Portraits, circa 1960-1965 (Box OS-Small)